[{"ID": 1, "Question": "The ________ model is the basis for today's computers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "von Neumann"}, {"ID": 2, "Question": "In a computer, the ________ subsystem stores data and programs.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "memory"}, {"ID": 3, "Question": "In a computer, the ________ subsystem performs calculations and\nlogical operations.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "ALU"}, {"ID": 4, "Question": "1-4 In a computer, the ________ subsystem accepts data and programs and\nsends processing results to output devices.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "input/output"}, {"ID": 5, "Question": "1-5 In a computer, the ________ subsystem serves as a manager of the\nother subsystems.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "control unit"}, {"ID": 6, "Question": "1-6 According to the von Neumann model, ________ are stored in memory.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "data and programs"}, {"ID": 7, "Question": "1-7 A step-by-step solution to a problem is called ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "an algorithm"}, {"ID": 8, "Question": "1-8 FORTRAN and COBOL are examples of ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "computer languages"}, {"ID": 9, "Question": "1-9 A 17th-century computing machine that could perform addition and\nsubtraction was the ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Pascaline"}, {"ID": 10, "Question": "1-10 ________ is a set of instructions in a computer language that tells the\ncomputer what to do with data.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A program"}, {"ID": 11, "Question": "1-11 ________ is the design and writing of a program in structured form.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Software engineering"}, {"ID": 12, "Question": "1-12 The first electronic special-purpose computer was called ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "ABC"}, {"ID": 13, "Question": "1-13 One of the first computers based on the von Neumann model was called ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "EDVAC"}, {"ID": 14, "Question": "1-14 The first computing machine to use the idea of storage and\nprogramming was called ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "the Jacquard loom"}, {"ID": 15, "Question": "1-15 ________ separated the programming task from computer operation tasks.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "High-level programming languages"}, {"ID": 16, "Question": "2-1 The base of the decimal number system is ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "10"}, {"ID": 17, "Question": "2-2 The base of the binary number system is ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "2"}, {"ID": 18, "Question": "2-3 The base of the octal number system is ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "8"}, {"ID": 19, "Question": "2-4 The base of the hexadecimal number system is ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "16"}, {"ID": 20, "Question": "2-5 When converting a decimal integer to base b, we repeatedly ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": ". divide by"}, {"ID": 21, "Question": "2-6 When converting a decimal fraction to base b, we repeatedly ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "multiply by"}, {"ID": 22, "Question": "3-2 In a set of 64 symbols, each symbol requires a bit pattern length of\n________ bits.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "6"}, {"ID": 23, "Question": "3-3 How many symbols can be represented by a bit pattern with ten bits?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "1024"}, {"ID": 24, "Question": "3-4 If the ASCII code for E is 1000101, then the ASCII code for e is\n________ . Answer the question without consulting the ASCII table.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "1100101"}, {"ID": 25, "Question": "3-5 A 32-bit code called ________ represents symbols in all languages.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Unicode"}, {"ID": 26, "Question": "3-6 An image can be represented in a computer using the ________ method.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "either bitmap or vector graphic"}, {"ID": 27, "Question": "3-7 In the ________ graphic method of representing an image in a computer,\neach pixel is assigned a bit patterns.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "bitmap"}, {"ID": 28, "Question": "3-8 In the ________ graphic method of representing an image in a computer,\nthe image is decomposed into a combination of geometrical figures.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "vector"}, {"ID": 29, "Question": "3-9 In the ________ graphic method of representing an image in a computer,\nre-scaling of the image creates a ragged or grainy image.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "bitmap"}, {"ID": 30, "Question": "3-10 When we want to store music in a computer, the audio signal must be\n________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "sampled, quantized, and coded"}, {"ID": 31, "Question": "3-11 A floating-point value after normalization is (1.0101) ? 2?4. What is the\nvalue of exponent section in the Excess-127 representation?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "123"}, {"ID": 32, "Question": "3-12 Assume a new Excess system uses 17 bits to represent the exponent\nsection. What is the bias value in this system?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "65535"}, {"ID": 33, "Question": "3-13 Which number representation method is often used to store the\nexponential value of a fractional part?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Excess"}, {"ID": 34, "Question": "3-14 In an Excess conversion, we ________ the number to be converted.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "add the bias number to"}, {"ID": 35, "Question": "3-15 When a fractional part is normalized, the computer stores the ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "the sign, exponent, and mantissa"}, {"ID": 36, "Question": "3-17 The combination of sign and mantissa of a real number in IEEE\nstandard floating point format is stored as an integer in the ________\nrepresentation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "sign-and-magnitude"}, {"ID": 37, "Question": "4-1 ________ is an arithmetic operation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Subtraction"}, {"ID": 38, "Question": "4-2 ________ is a logical bit operator.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "exclusive OR, unary NOT, or binary AND"}, {"ID": 39, "Question": "4-3 The ________ method of integer representation is the most common\nmethod for storing integers in computer memory.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "two's complement"}, {"ID": 40, "Question": "4-4 In two's complement addition, if there is a final carry after the left most\ncolumn addition, ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "discard it"}, {"ID": 41, "Question": "4-5 For an 8-bit allocation, the smallest decimal number that can be\nrepresented in two's complement form is ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "-128"}, {"ID": 42, "Question": "4-6 For an 8-bit allocation, the largest decimal number that can be\nrepresented in two's complement form is ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "127"}, {"ID": 43, "Question": "4-7 In two's complement representation with a 4-bit allocation, we get\n________ when we add 1 to 7.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "-8"}, {"ID": 44, "Question": "4-8 In two's complement representation with a 4-bit allocation, we get\n________ when we add 5 to 5.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "-6"}, {"ID": 45, "Question": "4-9 If the exponent in Excess_127 is binary 10000101, the exponent in\ndecimal is ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "6"}, {"ID": 46, "Question": "4-10 If we are adding two numbers, one of which has an exponent value of 7\nand the other an exponent value of 9, we need to shift the decimal point of the\nsmaller number ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "two places to the left"}, {"ID": 47, "Question": "4-11 ________ operator (s) takes two inputs to produce one output.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "AND, OR, or XOR"}, {"ID": 48, "Question": "4-12 The unary ________ operator inverts its single input.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "NOT"}, {"ID": 49, "Question": "4-13 ________ operator (s), if the input is two 0s, the output is 0.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "In AND, OR, or XOR"}, {"ID": 50, "Question": "4-14 ________ operator (s), if the input is two 1s, the output is 0.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "In only XOR"}, {"ID": 51, "Question": "4-15 For the binary AND operation, only an input of ________ gives an\noutput of 1.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "two 1s"}, {"ID": 52, "Question": "4-16 For the binary OR operation, only an input of ________ gives an output of 0.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "two 0s"}, {"ID": 53, "Question": "4-17 We use a bit pattern called a ________ to modify another bit pattern.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "mask"}, {"ID": 54, "Question": "4-18 To flip all the bits of a bit pattern, make a mask of all 1s and then\n________ the bit pattern and the mask.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "XOR"}, {"ID": 55, "Question": "4-19 To un-set (force to 0) all the bits of a bit pattern, make a mask of all 0s\nand then ________ the bit pattern and the mask.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "AND"}, {"ID": 56, "Question": "4-20 To set (force to 1) all the bits of a bit pattern, make a mask of all 1s and then ________ the bit pattern and the mask.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "OR"}, {"ID": 57, "Question": "5-1 The ________ is a computer subsystem that performs operations on\ndata.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "CPU"}, {"ID": 58, "Question": "5-2 ________ is a stand-alone storage location that holds data temporarily.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A register"}, {"ID": 59, "Question": "5-3 ________ is a unit that can add two inputs.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "An ALU"}, {"ID": 60, "Question": "5-4 A register in a CPU can hold ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "data, instruction, or program counter values"}, {"ID": 61, "Question": "5-5 A control unit with five wires can define up to ________ operations.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "32"}, {"ID": 62, "Question": "5-6 A word can be ________ bits.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "8, or 16, or 32"}, {"ID": 63, "Question": "5-7 If the memory address space is 16 MB and the word size is 8 bits, then________ bits are needed to access each word.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "24"}, {"ID": 64, "Question": "5-8 The data in ________ is erased if the computer is powered down.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "RAM"}, {"ID": 65, "Question": "5-9 ________ is a memory type with capacitors that need to be refreshed periodically.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "DRAM"}, {"ID": 66, "Question": "5-10 ________ is a memory type with traditional flip-flop gates to hold data.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "SRAM"}, {"ID": 67, "Question": "5-11 There are ________ bytes in 16 Terabytes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "2^16"}, {"ID": 68, "Question": "5-12 ________ can be programmed and erased using electronic impulses but can remain in a computer during erasure.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "EEPROM"}, {"ID": 69, "Question": "5-13 ________ is a type of memory in which the user, not the manufacturer,\nstores programs that cannot be overwritten.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "PROM"}, {"ID": 70, "Question": "5-14 Main memory in a computer usually consists of large amounts of________ speed memory.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "low"}, {"ID": 71, "Question": "5-15 A ________ is a storage device to which the user can write information only once.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "CD-R"}, {"ID": 72, "Question": "5-16 A ________ is a storage device that can undergo multiple writes and erasures.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "CD-RW"}, {"ID": 73, "Question": "5-17 The smallest storage area on a magnetic disk that can be accessed at one time is a ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "sector"}, {"ID": 74, "Question": "5-18 If the memory has 232 words, the address bus needs to have ________wires.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "32"}, {"ID": 75, "Question": "5-19 A control bus with eight wires can define ________ operations.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "256"}, {"ID": 76, "Question": "5-20 A ________ controller is a high-speed serial interface that transfers data in packets.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "USB and FireWire"}, {"ID": 77, "Question": "5-21 The three steps in the running of a program on a computer are\nperformed in the specific order ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "fetch, decode, and execute"}, {"ID": 78, "Question": "5-23 In the ________ method for synchronizing the operation of the CPU with an I/O device, the CPU is idle until the I/O operation is finished.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "programmed I/O"}, {"ID": 79, "Question": "5-24 In the ________ method for synchronizing the operation of the CPU with an I/O device, a large block of data can be passed from an I/O device to memory directly.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "DMA"}, {"ID": 80, "Question": "6-1 The TCP/IP model has ________ layers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "five"}, {"ID": 81, "Question": "6-2 The ________ layer of the TCP/IP protocol suite provides services for end users.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "application"}, {"ID": 82, "Question": "6-3. The ________ layer of the TCP/IP protocol suite transmits a bit stream over a physical medium.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "physical"}, {"ID": 83, "Question": "6-4 The ________ layer of the TCP/IP protocol suite is responsible for node-to-node delivery of a frame between two adjacent nodes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "data-link"}, {"ID": 84, "Question": "6-5 The ________ layer of the TCP/IP protocol suite is responsible for\nsource-to-destination delivery of the entire message.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "network"}, {"ID": 85, "Question": "6-6 What is the domain name in the email address kayla@nasa.gov?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "nasa.gov"}, {"ID": 86, "Question": "6-7 Which physical topology uses a hub or switch?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "star"}, {"ID": 87, "Question": "6-8 IP addresses are currently ________ bits in length.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "32"}, {"ID": 88, "Question": "6-9 ________ protocol (s) is one of the protocols in the transport layer.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "TCP, UDP, and SCTP"}, {"ID": 89, "Question": "6-10 ________ is a protocol for file transfer.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "FTP"}, {"ID": 90, "Question": "6-11 ________ is a protocol for email services.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "SMTP"}, {"ID": 91, "Question": "6-12 ________ is a protocol for accessing and transferring documents on the WWW.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "HTTP"}, {"ID": 92, "Question": "7-1 ________ is a program that facilitates the execution of other programs.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "An operating system"}, {"ID": 93, "Question": "7-2 ________ supervises the activity of each component in a computer\nsystem.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "An operating system"}, {"ID": 94, "Question": "7-3 Multi-programming requires a ________ operating-system.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "time-sharing"}, {"ID": 95, "Question": "7-4 ________ is multi-programming with swapping.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Demand paging"}, {"ID": 96, "Question": "7-5 ________ is multi-programming without swapping.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Partitioning"}, {"ID": 97, "Question": "7-6 In ________ , only one program can reside in memory for execution.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "mono-programming"}, {"ID": 98, "Question": "7-7 ________ is a multi-programming method in which multiple programs are entirely in memory with each program occupying a contiguous space.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Partitioning"}, {"ID": 99, "Question": "7-8 In paging, a program is divided into equally sized sections called________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "pages"}, {"ID": 100, "Question": "7-9 In ________ , the program can be divided into differently sized sections.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "demand segmentation"}, {"ID": 101, "Question": "7-10 In ________ , the program can be divided into equally sized sections called pages, but the pages need not be in memory at the same time for execution.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "demand paging"}, {"ID": 102, "Question": "7-11 A process in the ________ state can go to either the ready, terminated,or waiting states.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "running"}, {"ID": 103, "Question": "7-12 A process in the ready state goes to the running state when ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "it gets access to the CPU"}, {"ID": 104, "Question": "7-13 A program becomes a ________ when it is selected by the operating system and brought to the hold state.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "job"}, {"ID": 105, "Question": "7-14 Every process is ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a job and a program"}, {"ID": 106, "Question": "7-15 The ________ scheduler creates a process from a job and changes a process back to a job.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "job"}, {"ID": 107, "Question": "7-16 The ________ scheduler moves a process from one process state to another.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "process"}, {"ID": 108, "Question": "7-17 To prevent ________ , an operating system can put resource\nrestrictions on processes.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "deadlock"}, {"ID": 109, "Question": "7-18 ________ can occur if a process has too many resource restrictions.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Starvation"}, {"ID": 110, "Question": "7-19 The ________ manager is responsible for archiving and backup.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "file"}, {"ID": 111, "Question": "7-20 The ________ manager is responsible for access to I/O devices.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "device"}, {"ID": 112, "Question": "8-1 ________ is a step-by-step method for solving a problem or doing a task.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "An algorithm"}, {"ID": 113, "Question": "8-2 There are ________ basic constructs in computer -science.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "three"}, {"ID": 114, "Question": "8-3 The ________ construct tests a condition.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "decision"}, {"ID": 115, "Question": "8-4 The ________ construct uses a set of actions one after another.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "sequence"}, {"ID": 116, "Question": "8-5 The ________ construct handles repeated actions.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "repetition"}, {"ID": 117, "Question": "8-6 ________ is a pictorial representation of an algorithm.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A UML diagram"}, {"ID": 118, "Question": "8-7 ________ is an English-language-like representation of code.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Pseudocode"}, {"ID": 119, "Question": "8-8 ________ is a basic algorithm that adds a list of numbers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Summation"}, {"ID": 120, "Question": "8-9 ________ is a basic algorithm that multiplies a list of numbers.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Product"}, {"ID": 121, "Question": "8-10 ________ is a basic algorithm that arranges data according to its value.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Sorting"}, {"ID": 122, "Question": "8-11 The items are divided into two lists (sorted and unsorted) ________\nsort.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "in selection, bubble, or insertion"}, {"ID": 123, "Question": "8-12 In ________ sort, the item that goes into the sorted list is always the first item in the unsorted list.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "insertion"}, {"ID": 124, "Question": "8-13 In ________ sort, the smallest item from the unsorted list is swapped with the item at the beginning of the unsorted list.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "selection"}, {"ID": 125, "Question": "8-14 In ________ sort, the smallest item moves to the beginning of the\nunsorted list. There is no one-to-one swapping.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "bubble"}, {"ID": 126, "Question": "8-15 ________ is a basic algorithm in which we want to find the location of a target in a list of items.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Searching"}, {"ID": 127, "Question": "8-16 We use a ________ search for an unordered list.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "sequential"}, {"ID": 128, "Question": "8-17 We use a ________ search for an ordered list.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "binary"}, {"ID": 129, "Question": "8-18 ________ is a process in which an algorithm calls itself.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Recursion"}, {"ID": 130, "Question": "9-1 The only language understood by computer hardware is a ________\nlanguage.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "machine"}, {"ID": 131, "Question": "9-2 C, C++, and Java can be classified as ________ languages.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "high-level"}, {"ID": 132, "Question": "9-3 FORTRAN is a(n) ________ language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "procedural"}, {"ID": 133, "Question": "9-4 Pascal is a(n) ________ language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": ". procedural"}, {"ID": 134, "Question": "9-5 Java is a(n) ________ language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "object-oriented"}, {"ID": 135, "Question": "9-6 LISP is a(n) ________ language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "functional"}, {"ID": 136, "Question": "9-7 ________ is a common language in the business -environment.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "COBOL"}, {"ID": 137, "Question": "9-8 ________ is a popular object-oriented language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Java"}, {"ID": 138, "Question": "9-9 A ________ program can be either an application or an applet.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Java"}, {"ID": 139, "Question": "9-10 LISP and Scheme are both ________ languages.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "functional"}, {"ID": 140, "Question": "9-11 Prolog is an example of a(n) ________ language.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "declarative"}, {"ID": 141, "Question": "10-1 One phase in system development is ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "analysis"}, {"ID": 142, "Question": "10-2 Defining the users, requirements, and methods is part of the ________phase.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "analysis"}, {"ID": 143, "Question": "10-3 In the system development process, writing the program is part of the________ phase.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "implementation"}, {"ID": 144, "Question": "10-4 In the system development process, structure charts are tools used in the ________ phase.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "design"}, {"ID": 145, "Question": "10-5 Testing a software system can involve ________ testing.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "both black-box and glass-box"}, {"ID": 146, "Question": "10-6 ________ is the breaking up of a large project into smaller parts.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Modularization"}, {"ID": 147, "Question": "10-7 ________ is a measure of how tightly two modules are bound to each other.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Coupling"}, {"ID": 148, "Question": "10-8 ________ between modules in a software system must be minimized.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Coupling"}, {"ID": 149, "Question": "10-9 ________ between modules in a software system must be maximized.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Cohesion"}, {"ID": 150, "Question": "11-1 A data structure can be ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "an array, a record, or a linked list"}, {"ID": 151, "Question": "11-2 An array that consists of just rows and columns is a ________ array.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "one-dimensional"}, {"ID": 152, "Question": "11-3 Each element in a record is called ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a field"}, {"ID": 153, "Question": "11-4 All the members of a record must be ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "related types"}, {"ID": 154, "Question": "11-5 ________ is an ordered collection of data in which each element\ncontains the location of the next element.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A linked list"}, {"ID": 155, "Question": "11-6 In a linked list, each element contains ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "data and a link"}, {"ID": 156, "Question": "11-7 The ________ is a pointer that identifies the next element in the linked list.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "link"}, {"ID": 157, "Question": "11-8 Given a linked list called children, the pointer variable children identifies\n________ element of the linked list.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "the first"}, {"ID": 158, "Question": "11-9 An empty linked list consists of ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a null head pointer"}, {"ID": 159, "Question": "11-10 To traverse a list, you need a ________ pointer.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "walking"}, {"ID": 160, "Question": "12-1 In an abstract data type, ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "the ADT implementation is hidden"}, {"ID": 161, "Question": "12-2 A stack is a ________ structure.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "LIFO"}, {"ID": 162, "Question": "12-3 A (n) ________ list is also known as a queue.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "FIFO"}, {"ID": 163, "Question": "12-4 If A is the first data element input into a stack, followed by B, C, and D,\nthen ________ is the first element to be removed.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "D"}, {"ID": 164, "Question": "12-5 If A is the first data element input into a queue, followed by B, C, and\nD, then ________ is the first element to be removed.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A"}, {"ID": 165, "Question": "12-6 The pop operation ________ of the stack.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "deletes an item from the top"}, {"ID": 166, "Question": "12-7 The push operation ________ of the stack.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "inserts an item at the top"}, {"ID": 167, "Question": "12-8 In a binary tree, each node has ________ two subtrees.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "at most"}, {"ID": 168, "Question": "12-9 In preorder traversal of a binary tree, the ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "root is processed first"}, {"ID": 169, "Question": "12-10 In ________ traversal of a binary tree, the right subtree is processed", "Choices": [], "Answer": "inorder"}, {"ID": 170, "Question": "12-11 In postorder traversal of a binary tree, the root is processed ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "last"}, {"ID": 171, "Question": "12-12 In postorder traversal of a binary tree, the left subtree is processed________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "first"}, {"ID": 172, "Question": "12-13 In ________ traversal of a binary tree, the left subtree is processed\nlast.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "preorder"}, {"ID": 173, "Question": "12-14 In an inorder traversal of a binary tree, the root is processed ________.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "second"}, {"ID": 174, "Question": "13-1 ________ file can be accessed randomly.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Any"}, {"ID": 175, "Question": "13-2 ________ file can be accessed sequentially.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A sequential"}, {"ID": 176, "Question": "13-3 When a sequential file is updated, the ________ file gets the actual\nupdate.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "new master"}, {"ID": 177, "Question": "13-4 When a sequential file is updated, the ________ file contains a list of all errors occurring during the update process.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "error report"}, {"ID": 178, "Question": "13-5 When a sequential file is updated, the ________ file contains the\nchanges to be applied.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "transaction"}, {"ID": 179, "Question": "13-6 After a sequential file is updated, the ________ file contains the most current data.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "new master"}, {"ID": 180, "Question": "13-7 If the transaction file key is 20 and the first master file key is 25, then we ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "add the new record to the new master file"}, {"ID": 181, "Question": "13-8 If the transaction file key is 20 with a delete code and the master file key is 20, then we ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "delete the data"}, {"ID": 182, "Question": "13-9 An indexed file consists of ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "an index and random data file"}, {"ID": 183, "Question": "13-10 The index of an indexed file has ________ fields.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "two"}, {"ID": 184, "Question": "13-11 In the ________ hashing method, selected digits are extracted from the key and used as the address.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "digit extraction"}, {"ID": 185, "Question": "13-12 In the ________ hashing method, the key is divided by the file size,\nand the address is the remainder plus 1.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "modulo division"}, {"ID": 186, "Question": "13-13 In the ________ hashing method, there are no synonyms or collisions.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "direct"}, {"ID": 187, "Question": "13-14 ________ are keys that hash to the same location in the data file.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Synonyms"}, {"ID": 188, "Question": "13-15 When a hashing algorithm produces an address for an insertion key and that address is already occupied, it is called a ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "collision"}, {"ID": 189, "Question": "13-16 The address produced by a hashing algorithm is the ________\naddress.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "home"}, {"ID": 190, "Question": "13-17 The ________ area is the file area that contains all the home\naddresses.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "prime"}, {"ID": 191, "Question": "13-18 In the ________ collision resolution method, we try to put data that cannot be placed in location 123 into location 124.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "open addressing"}, {"ID": 192, "Question": "14-1 In a three-level DBMS architecture, the layer that interacts directly with the hardware is the________ level.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "internal"}, {"ID": 193, "Question": "14-2 In a three-level DBMS architecture, the ________ level determines where data is actually stored on the storage devices.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "internal"}, {"ID": 194, "Question": "14-3 The ________ level of a three-level DBMS architecture defines the logical view of the data.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "conceptual"}, {"ID": 195, "Question": "14-4 The data model and the schema of a DBMS are often defined at the ________ level.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "conceptual"}, {"ID": 196, "Question": "14-5 In a three-level DBMS architecture, the ________ level interacts directly with the users.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "external"}, {"ID": 197, "Question": "14-6 Of the various database models, the ________ model is the most prevalent today.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "relational"}, {"ID": 198, "Question": "14-7 Each column in a relation is called ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "an attribute"}, {"ID": 199, "Question": "14-8 Each row in a relation is called ________", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a tuple"}, {"ID": 200, "Question": "14-9 A unary operator is applied to ________ relation(s) and creates an output of ________ relation(s).", "Choices": [], "Answer": "one, two"}, {"ID": 201, "Question": "14-10 A binary operator is applied to ________ relation(s) and creates an output of ________ relation(s).", "Choices": [], "Answer": "two, one"}, {"ID": 202, "Question": "14-11 The unary ________ operation always results in a relation that has exactly one more row than the original relation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "insert"}, {"ID": 203, "Question": "14-12 If you want to change the value of an attribute of a tuple, you use the ________ operation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "update"}, {"ID": 204, "Question": "14-13 The operation that takes two relations and combines them based on common attributes is the ________ operation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "join"}, {"ID": 205, "Question": "14-14 If you need to delete an attribute in a relation, you can use the ________ operation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "project"}, {"ID": 206, "Question": "14-15 You want to create a relation called New that contains tuples that belong to both relation A and relation B. For this, you can use the ________ operation.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "intersection"}, {"ID": 207, "Question": "14-16 Which of the following is a unary operator?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "project"}, {"ID": 208, "Question": "14-17 Which of the following is a binary operator?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "difference"}, {"ID": 209, "Question": "14-18 ________ is a declarative language used on relational databases.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "SQL"}, {"ID": 210, "Question": "15-1 Data is compressed using a dictionary with indexes to strings. This is ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Lempel Ziv encoding"}, {"ID": 211, "Question": "15-2 A string of one hundred 0s is replaced by two markers, a 0, and the number 100. This is ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "run-length encoding"}, {"ID": 212, "Question": "15-4 In a ________ data compression method, the received data is an exact copy of the original message.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "lossless"}, {"ID": 213, "Question": "15-5 ________ data compression method, the received data need not be an exact copy of the original message.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "In MP3, JPEG, or MPEG"}, {"ID": 214, "Question": "15-3 ________ is an example of lossy compression.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "JPEG"}, {"ID": 215, "Question": "15-6 ________ encoding is a lossless data compression method.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Huffman, run-length, or LZ"}, {"ID": 216, "Question": "15-7 In ________ encoding, the more frequently occurring characters have shorter codes than the less frequently occurring characters.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Huffman"}, {"ID": 217, "Question": "15-8 In ________ encoding, PPPPPPPPPPPPPPP can be replaced by P15.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "run-length"}, {"ID": 218, "Question": "15-9 LZ encoding requires ________ .", "Choices": [], "Answer": "a dictionary, a buffer, and an algorithm"}, {"ID": 219, "Question": "15-10 JPEG encoding involves ________ , a process that reveals the redundancies in a block.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "the discrete cosine transform"}, {"ID": 220, "Question": "15-11 In JPEG encoding, the ________ process breaks the original picture into smaller blocks and assigns a value to each pixel in a block.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "blocking"}, {"ID": 221, "Question": "15-12 The last step in JPEG, ________ , removes redundancies.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "compression"}, {"ID": 222, "Question": "15-13 ________ is a lossy compression method for pictures and graphics, whereas ________ is a lossy compression method for video.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "JPEG, MPEG"}, {"ID": 223, "Question": "Physical", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is OSI layer of repeater? \nData Link\nNetwork\nPhysical\nTransport"}, {"ID": 224, "Question": "Time slicing", "Choices": [], "Answer": "An OS method of allowing multiple processes to share the CPU is: *\n1/1\nTime slicing\nMultiuser\nMulti Access\nMulti purpose"}, {"ID": 225, "Question": "Partitioned and formatted", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Before a disk can be used, it must be: *\n1/1\nErased and set up\nPartitioned and formatted\nDeleted and formatted\nErased and formatted"}, {"ID": 226, "Question": "Data Link", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the OSI layers is responsible for guaranteed delivery of data? *\n1/1\nTransport\nNetwork\nData Link\nPresentation"}, {"ID": 227, "Question": "Transfer Web pages", "Choices": [], "Answer": "The purpose of HTTP is to *\n0/1\nFormat Web pages\nTransfer Web pages\nTransfer address\nTransfer data"}, {"ID": 228, "Question": "Ctrl+Alt +Del key", "Choices": [], "Answer": "In Windows , you can see the Task manager by using which of the following? *\n1/1\nTab +Alt +Del key\nShift +Alt +Del key\nCtrl+Alt +Del key\nFn +Alt +Del key"}, {"ID": 229, "Question": "Fiber-optic cable", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which type of guided medium is the least susceptible to attenuation and inductance? *\n0/1\nCoaxial cable\nCopper wire\nFiber-optic cable\nGolden wire"}, {"ID": 230, "Question": "64", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What is the positional value of the 7 in the base 8 number 2715? *\n1/1\n16\n8\n64\n100"}, {"ID": 231, "Question": "XOR", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is not one of the basic Boolean operators? *\n1/1\nAND\n. OR\nNOT\nXOR"}, {"ID": 232, "Question": "Network", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is OSI layer of Router *\n1/1\nData Link\nNetwork\nPhysical\nTransport"}, {"ID": 233, "Question": "Disk Operating System", "Choices": [], "Answer": "DOS stands for: *\n1/1\nDemand Open Sources\nDisk Operating System\nDevice Outer Shell\nDirect Operating System"}, {"ID": 234, "Question": "DOS", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is not a multitasking OS? *\n1/1\nLinux\nUNIX\nWindows\nDOS"}, {"ID": 235, "Question": "Formatting", "Choices": [], "Answer": "The process of arranges the disk's surface into addressable areas and sets up the disk's basic directory tree structure *\n1/1\nPartitioning\nSet up\nBooting\nFormatting"}, {"ID": 236, "Question": "1100010000111010", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What binary value is equivalent to the hex number C43A? *\n1/1\n1100100100010110\n1100110101111010\n1100010000111010\n1100001101011101"}, {"ID": 237, "Question": "ALU", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which part of the CPU is responsible for mathematical operations? *\n1/1\nCU\nALU\nRLU\nVLSI"}, {"ID": 238, "Question": "They were cheaper, smaller, and cooler than tubes and lasted longer.", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What features of transistors made them superior for computers, compared with vacuum tubes? *\n1/1\nThey were more expensive than tubes but lasted longer and were cooler in temperature.\nThey didn't last as long as tubes but were less expensive.\nThey were cheaper and smaller than tubes.\nThey were cheaper, smaller, and cooler than tubes and lasted longer."}, {"ID": 239, "Question": "Linux operating system", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Today, Microsoft considers its major competition in operating systems to be what system? *\n0/1\nControl Data Corporation OS\nSega Games operating system\nLinux operating system\nMac OS X"}, {"ID": 240, "Question": "Cache memory", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Linux operating system\nHigh-speed __________________ is used to speed processing in a computer system *\n0/1\nMass storage\nCache memory\nROM"}, {"ID": 241, "Question": "Flip-flop", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following circuit types is used to create SRAM? *\n1/1\nDecoder\nFlip-flop\nLCD\nROM"}, {"ID": 242, "Question": "256 Kbps to 1.5 Mbps", "Choices": [], "Answer": "DSL speeds range from: *\n1/1\n256 Kbps to 1.5 Mbps\n256 Mbps to 15 Mbps\n56 Kbps to 256 Kbps\n100 Kbps to 156 Kbps"}, {"ID": 243, "Question": "FDM and TDM", "Choices": [], "Answer": "DSL is a combination of what two types of multiplexing? *\n1/1\nAM and FM\nFDM and FM\nAM and TDM\nFDM and TDM"}, {"ID": 244, "Question": "1000011111", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What is the binary equivalent of the decimal number 543? *\n1/1\n11111011110111\n101100111\n1011010011\n1000011111"}, {"ID": 245, "Question": "Bus", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A _______________ in computer terminology is a set of wires and protocols designed to facilitate data transfer *\n1/1\nGate\nBus\nBoolean circuit\nCPU"}, {"ID": 246, "Question": "Wireless", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is not one of the OSI model layers? *\n1/1\nData link\nWireless\nTransport\nApplication"}, {"ID": 247, "Question": "Root", "Choices": [], "Answer": "The main level of a disk is called the: *\n1/1\nRoot\nPlatform\nSector\nDirectory"}, {"ID": 248, "Question": "Point of Presence", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Internet Providers maintain a Switching center called a: *\n0/1\nEnd user\nInternet\nPoint of Presence\nAccess point"}, {"ID": 249, "Question": "16", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What is the positional value of the A in the hexadecimal number C4A6? *\n1/1\n10\n16\n160\n100"}, {"ID": 250, "Question": "15,373", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What base 10 value is equivalent to 3C0D of base 16? *\n1/1\n32,767\n15,373\n68,536\n10,125"}, {"ID": 251, "Question": "Star", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which topology has become more popular with the advent of the Internet and home networking? *\n1/1\nToken ring\nStar\nBus\nRing"}, {"ID": 252, "Question": "ROM", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which type of memory can't be written to easily? *\nRAM\nSRAM\nROM\nFlip-flop"}, {"ID": 253, "Question": "Interrupt", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which type of I/O processing is most efficient? *\n0/1\nBoolean\nPolling\nLogic\nInterrupt"}, {"ID": 254, "Question": "129", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What numeric value in base 10 does the binary number 10000001 represent? *\n1/1\n119\n139\n129\nNone of the above"}, {"ID": 255, "Question": "Data Link", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is OSI layer of Switch? *\n1/1\nData Link\nNetwork\nPhysical\nTransport"}, {"ID": 256, "Question": "DEAD", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What numeric value in hexadecimal is equivalent to the binary number 1101111010101101 *\n1/1\nBCAF\nBE6C\n6FAD\nDEAD"}, {"ID": 257, "Question": "802.11", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following standards is used in wireless networking? *\n1/1\n802.15\nOSI\n802.11\nTCP"}, {"ID": 258, "Question": "SRAM", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following memory types is the fastest? *\n1/1\nDRAM\nROM\nXOR\nSRAM"}, {"ID": 259, "Question": "16", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What is the minimum number of bits required to represent 256 colors? *\n0/1\n4\n8\n16\n32"}, {"ID": 260, "Question": "Algebraic expressions", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Boolean expressions are simplified through the use of: *\n0/1\nBasic identities\nGate logic\nAlgebraic expressions\nSpecialized circuits"}, {"ID": 261, "Question": "BIOS", "Choices": [], "Answer": "The _______________ contains instructions and data that provide the startup program for a computer. *\n1/1\nRAM\nDRAM\nBIOS\nCPU"}, {"ID": 262, "Question": "False", "Choices": [], "Answer": "In Windows, the MD command must be used to create a folder *\n1/1\nTrue\nFalse"}, {"ID": 263, "Question": "Interpreter", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following translates a program's statements, one by one, into a language the computer can understand? *\n1/1\nCompiler\nInterpreter\nTranslator\nIDE"}, {"ID": 264, "Question": "Router", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which Internet component is responsible for decrementing the TTL field? *\n1/1\nRouter\nSwitch\nDNS\nGate way"}, {"ID": 265, "Question": "<A>", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which HTML tag is used to provide links to other pages? *\n1/1\n<HTTP>\n<LINK>\n<A>\n<P>"}, {"ID": 266, "Question": "Compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following converts source code into a computer language and results in an executable file *\n1/1\nInterpreter\nCompiler\nIDE\nTranslator"}, {"ID": 267, "Question": "None of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is not a responsibility of the file system? *\n1/1\nCreating files\nManipulating files\nRenaming files\nNone of the above"}, {"ID": 268, "Question": "Prototype", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A ... is a standard or typical example of how something might work, but without all the built-in functionality. *\n1/1\nFlowchart\nPrototype\nDesign document\nData dictionary"}, {"ID": 269, "Question": "HTTP", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following protocols makes the Web possible? *\n1/1\nFTP\nTelnet\nHTTP\nIP"}, {"ID": 270, "Question": "TCP", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which portion of the TCP/IP protocol suite provides error detection and correction *\n1/1\nTCP\nIP\nBoth\nNeither"}, {"ID": 271, "Question": "None of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which is not included as a task of software engineering? *\n1/1\nCommunicating with clients in meetings\nDesigning screens\nWriting the application\nCreating a design document\nNone of the above"}, {"ID": 272, "Question": "Algorithm", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which is not a type of control structure? *\n1/1\nInvocation\nTop down\nAlgorithm\nSelection"}, {"ID": 273, "Question": "Thousands", "Choices": [], "Answer": "How many DNS servers does the Internet have? *\n1/1\n256\n512\nThousands\nMillions"}, {"ID": 274, "Question": "Domain", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What is the set of possible values for a column? *\n1/1\nIndex\nTable\nSQL\nDomain"}, {"ID": 275, "Question": "Eliminate repeated fields", "Choices": [], "Answer": "First normal DB form say *\n1/1\nNo non key columns depend on another nonkey column\nEvery column that's not part of the primary key is fully dependent on the primary key.\nEliminate repeated fields\nAll of the above"}, {"ID": 276, "Question": "C++", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is not a valid DBMS? *\n1/1\nSQL Server\nC++\nOracle\nDB2"}, {"ID": 277, "Question": "Degradation", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which is not a valid software development model? *\n1/1\nWaterfall\nDegradation\nEvolution\nSpiral\nIncremental"}, {"ID": 278, "Question": "Worm", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A....... is a bot that actively reproduces itself across a network *\n1/1\nVirus\nTroyjan\nWorm\nNone of the above"}, {"ID": 279, "Question": "passwords", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Use ...................................to protect everything Startup, e-mail, router, phone, PDA, screen saver *\n1/1\nBack up\npasswords\nlocks\nkeys"}, {"ID": 280, "Question": "HTML", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is not an Internet-related protocol? *\n1/1\nHTTP\nHTML\nFTP\nTCP"}, {"ID": 281, "Question": "Virus", "Choices": [], "Answer": ".............. are uninvited guest programs on your computer with the potential to damage files and the operating system *\n1/1\nVirus\nWorm\nBot\nTroyjan"}, {"ID": 282, "Question": "Efficient disk use on small volumes", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which is not an advantage of using NTFS? *\n1/1\nJournaling\nFile encryption\nEfficient disk use on small volumes\nSecurity"}, {"ID": 283, "Question": "Primary key", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What uniquely identifies a row in a table? *\n1/1\nIndex\nFiel\nPrimary key\nTuple"}, {"ID": 284, "Question": "1", "Choices": [], "Answer": "How many IP addresses are presented to the Internet when NAT is used? *\n1/1\n1\n16\n 3\n64"}, {"ID": 285, "Question": "65,536", "Choices": [], "Answer": "5. How many possible ports are allowed in TCP? *\n1/1\n8\n16\n65,536\n16,137,285"}, {"ID": 286, "Question": "80", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What is the standard port number for HTTP? *\n1/1\n16\n32\n64\n80"}, {"ID": 287, "Question": "Array", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A(n) __________ is a data structure consisting of contiguous memory locations *\n1/1\nQueue\nStack\nArray\nTree"}, {"ID": 288, "Question": "Flowchart", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A ... is used as a visual model for describing a program's logical steps *\n1/1\nClass diagram\nFlowchart\nUse case diagram\nDesign document"}, {"ID": 289, "Question": "DHCP", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which Internet protocol is used to assign IP addresses dynamically? *\n1/1\nTCP\nDHCP\nHTTP\nDNS"}, {"ID": 290, "Question": "ORDER BY", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following SQL SELECT options is used to organize the data being returned? *\n1/1\nSORT BY\nORDER BY\nWHERE\nARRANGE"}, {"ID": 291, "Question": "Flash", "Choices": [], "Answer": "With _________ the microchip is organized so that a section of memory cells are erased in a single action. *\n1/1\nROM\nFlash\nPROM\nEEPROM"}, {"ID": 292, "Question": "None of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which should not be included in the design document? *\n1/1\nProject objectives and requirements\nCost analysis\nFeasibility study\nCopies of screens and reports\nNone of the above"}, {"ID": 293, "Question": "Assembly", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which is not an example of a high-level programming language? *\n1/1\nAda\nAssembly\nC++\nJava"}, {"ID": 294, "Question": "A blueprint that shows an application's functionality", "Choices": [], "Answer": "A design document is used as: *\n1/1\nA way to bill the client more\nA blueprint that shows an application's functionality\nA replacement for pseudocode when writing a program\nNone of the above"}, {"ID": 295, "Question": "Compiler", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following converts source code into a computer language and results in an executable file? *\n1/1\nInterpreter\nCompiler\nTranslator\nIDE"}, {"ID": 296, "Question": "Add the data", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which is not a step of the database design process? *\n1/1\nCreate the tables\nCreate the relationships\nInvestigate\nAdd the data"}, {"ID": 297, "Question": "minimize drive head movement?", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Disk Defragmenter utility is used to *\n1/1\nreorganize tracks\nminimize drive head movement?\nminimize files\nreorganize sector"}, {"ID": 298, "Question": "Variable", "Choices": [], "Answer": "What is a name used to identify a specific location and value in memory? *\n1/1\nVariable\nOperator\nControl structure\nObject"}, {"ID": 299, "Question": "Data dictionary", "Choices": [], "Answer": "The document responsible for describing the type of data stored in the database is called the *\n1/1\nDesign document\nData dictionary\nUML diagram\nSDLC"}, {"ID": 300, "Question": "Troyjan", "Choices": [], "Answer": "is a program that poses as an innocent program *\n1/1\nWorm\nBot\nTroyjan\nVirus"}, {"ID": 301, "Question": "SMTP", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which of the following is an example of a high-level protocol? *\n1/1\nTCP\nIP\nDHCP\nSMTP"}, {"ID": 302, "Question": "None of the above", "Choices": [], "Answer": "Which is not a type of programming language? *\n1/1\nLow-level\nAssembly\nHigh-level\nMachine\nNone of the above"}]